When is it time to slow down?
什么时候才是该放慢生活节奏的时候呢？
Is it when you reach middle age, when you can draw your pension or even later?
是当你步入中年的时候，当你可以领取养老金的时候，还是更晚呢？
Queen Elizabeth II turned 90 this year and there are not many signs that she's taking it easy.
伊丽莎白二世女王今年90岁了，却没有多少迹象表明她在放松。
Last year alone the monarch carried out over 300 engagements.
仅去年一年，这位君主就参加了300多项活动。
Longevity has long been a topic of discussion in Britain.
长寿一直是英国讨论的一个话题。
What's likely to make us live longer?
什么有可能让我们活得更久呢？
According to Professor Sarah Harper, from the Oxford Institute of Population Ageing, just over half your chances of living a long life come down to luck.
牛津人口老龄化研究所的莎拉·哈珀教授表示，你长寿的可能性中，略超过一半取决于运气。
She says: "If you have parents and grandparents who made it into their eighties and nineties there's a chance you have inherited good genes.
她说：“如果你父母和祖父母都活到了八九十岁，那么你就有可能遗传了良好的基因。
You are more likely to have a strong immune system and are less likely to develop chronic diseases."
你更有可能拥有强大的免疫系统，并且不太可能患上慢性疾病。”
Lucky you, then.
那你很幸运了。
But don't rely on that because bad habits can spoil everything.
但别指望这个，因为坏习惯会毁了一切。
Half of long-term smokers die prematurely.
长期吸烟的人中有一半会过早死亡。
Smoking causes heart disease, lung cancer and other illnesses.
吸烟会引发心脏病、肺癌和其他疾病。
A poor diet and lack of exercise can lead to obesity, which reduces your life expectancy by between three and 10 years, says the National Health Service in Britain.
英国国民医疗服务体系表示，不良的饮食习惯和缺乏锻炼会导致肥胖，这会使你的预期寿命缩短3到10年。
But it's not worth stressing out about how long you're going to stick around.
但不值得为你还能活多久而焦虑。
Stress can take years off someone's life.
压力会缩短人的寿命。
A study published in the British Medical Journal found even low-level stress raises the risk of heart attacks and strokes by 20% and you don't want that, do you?
发表在《英国医学杂志》上的一项研究发现，即使是轻微的压力也会使心脏病发作和中风的风险增加20%，你可不想这样，不是吗？
After you've ticked all the boxes — genes, healthy living, keeping cool — you might have almost guaranteed a long life.
在你满足了所有条件——良好的基因、健康的生活方式、保持心态平和——之后，你几乎就可以保证长寿了。
But for what?
但为了什么而长寿呢？
That's the final piece of the jigsaw.
这是拼图的最后一块。
Having a purpose in life can also make you live longer.
有生活目标也能让你活得更久。
Some people engage in charity work to keep active, others get involved in initiatives in their community.
一些人参加慈善工作来保持活力，另一些人参与社区的活动项目。
It gives them a reason to wake up in the morning — even if the joints creak a little.
这给了他们早上起床的理由——即使关节有点嘎吱作响。
Professor Harper says that caring for others can make you feel valued.
哈珀教授说，关爱他人能让你感到自己有价值。
It must feel good to be appreciated — by people around you, by a nation.
被周围的人、被一个国家赏识，这种感觉肯定很棒。
Happy 90th birthday, Your Majesty!
女王陛下，祝您90岁生日快乐！